import type { QuizQuestion } from './quiz-data';

export const quizDataEn: QuizQuestion[] = [
    {
        question: "The Sun is considered a star of ........ size.",
        options: ["Medium", "Large", "Small", "Giant"],
        correct: "Medium"
    },
    {
        question: "The Sun can contain .......... Earth planets.",
        options: ["1,300", "1.3 million", "1.3 billion", "1.3"],
        correct: "1.3 million"
    },
    {
        question: "The predominant element in the Sun is ..........",
        options: ["Helium", "Hydrogen", "Carbon", "Oxygen"],
        correct: "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
        question: "Where does nuclear fusion occur?",
        options: ["The Core", "The Surface", "The Corona", "The Chromosphere"],
        correct: "The Core"
    },
    {
        question: "The distance between the Earth and the Sun is ..........",
        options: ["150 km", "150,000 km", "150 million km", "150 m"],
        correct: "150 million km"
    },
    {
        question: "Which planet is closest to the Sun?",
        options: ["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Uranus"],
        correct: "Mercury"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the smallest planet in the solar system?",
        options: ["Venus", "Jupiter", "Earth", "Mercury"],
        correct: "Mercury"
    },
    {
        question: "The temperature difference between day and night on Mercury's surface is .......... degrees Celsius.",
        options: ["250", "180", "430", "610"],
        correct: "610"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of moons of Mercury is ........",
        options: ["3", "4", "1", "Zero"],
        correct: "Zero"
    },
    {
        question: "The planet nicknamed Earth's twin is ..........",
        options: ["Jupiter", "Venus", "Mercury", "Mars"],
        correct: "Venus"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of moons of Venus is ........",
        options: ["3", "7", "1", "Zero"],
        correct: "Zero"
    },
    {
        question: "Which planet rotates on its axis in the opposite direction to the other planets?",
        options: ["Jupiter", "Venus", "Mercury", "Mars"],
        correct: "Venus"
    },
    {
        question: "Which substance is common in Venus's atmosphere?",
        options: ["Carbon Dioxide", "Oxygen", "Hydrogen", "Water Vapor"],
        correct: "Carbon Dioxide"
    },
    {
        question: "The hottest planet in the solar system is ..........",
        options: ["Mercury", "Venus", "Earth", "Uranus"],
        correct: "Venus"
    },
    {
        question: "The planet where a day is longer than a year is .......",
        options: ["Mercury", "Venus", "Neptune", "Uranus"],
        correct: "Venus"
    },
    {
        question: "What distinguishes Earth from the rest of the planets in the solar system?",
        options: ["The only planet suitable for life", "The smallest in the solar system", "The closest planet to the Sun", "It has no atmosphere"],
        correct: "The only planet suitable for life"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the reason for the four seasons on Earth?",
        options: ["Earth's rotation on its axis", "Earth's axial tilt", "Tectonic plate movement", "The Moon's gravity"],
        correct: "Earth's axial tilt"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Earth's surface made of?",
        options: ["Land only", "Oceans only", "Land and water", "Desert only"],
        correct: "Land and water"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the result of tectonic plate movement?",
        options: ["Day and night phenomenon", "Tide phenomenon", "Earthquakes and volcanoes", "The four seasons"],
        correct: "Earthquakes and volcanoes"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Mars's atmosphere composed of?",
        options: ["Oxygen", "Hydrogen", "Carbon Dioxide", "Nitrogen"],
        correct: "Carbon Dioxide"
    },
    {
        question: "The planet nicknamed the Red Planet is ..........",
        options: ["Jupiter", "Venus", "Mercury", "Mars"],
        correct: "Mars"
    },
    {
        question: "The largest volcano in the solar system is on the planet ........",
        options: ["Mercury", "Mars", "Neptune", "Uranus"],
        correct: "Mars"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of moons of Mars is ........",
        options: ["3", "2", "14", "5"],
        correct: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "How long is a day on Mars?",
        options: ["12 Earth hours", "36 Earth hours and 39 minutes", "48 hours", "24 hours and 39 minutes"],
        correct: "24 hours and 39 minutes"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the weather characteristics on Mars?",
        options: ["Huge dust storms", "Heavy rains", "Light winds", "High temperature"],
        correct: "Huge dust storms"
    },
    {
        question: "The dominant element in Saturn's composition is?",
        options: ["Helium", "Hydrogen", "Carbon", "Silicon"],
        correct: "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
        question: "Saturn is considered a ............... planet.",
        options: ["Gas", "Rocky", "Liquid", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Gas"
    },
    {
        question: "The planet famous for its rings is ............ (Jupiter, Saturn, Mars, Mercury)",
        options: ["Jupiter", "Saturn", "Mars", "Mercury"],
        correct: "Saturn"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of moons orbiting Saturn is .......",
        options: ["140", "130", "150", "95", "13"],
        correct: "140"
    },
    {
        question: "How many stars are in the solar system?",
        options: ["3", "1", "2", "Zero"],
        correct: "1"
    },
    {
        question: "Mercury's atmosphere is .........",
        options: ["Thick", "Weak", "Medium", "Has no atmosphere"],
        correct: "Weak"
    },
    {
        question: "What distinguishes Earth from Venus and Mars?",
        options: ["The day is much longer", "Its surface has volcanic mountains", "There is no life on it", "It has a balanced atmosphere"],
        correct: "It has a balanced atmosphere"
    },
    {
        question: "The planet with a density less than water is ..........",
        options: ["Jupiter", "Saturn", "Mars", "Mercury"],
        correct: "Saturn"
    },
    {
        question: "The largest of Saturn's moons is ...............",
        options: ["Enceladus", "Titan", "Io", "Mimas"],
        correct: "Titan"
    },
    {
        question: "The Great Red Spot is a ...........",
        options: ["Huge storm", "Iron oxide rocks", "Mountain", "Depression"],
        correct: "Huge storm"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of Jupiter's moons is ...........",
        options: ["90", "85", "105", "140", "95"],
        correct: "95"
    },
    {
        question: "Which planet has the strongest magnetic field?",
        options: ["Earth", "Mercury", "Jupiter", "Neptune"],
        correct: "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        question: "The largest moon in the solar system is ........",
        options: ["Titan", "Phobos", "Enceladus", "Ganymede"],
        correct: "Ganymede"
    },
    {
        question: "Uranus is described as ...........",
        options: ["A small planet", "A gas giant planet", "An ice giant planet", "A dwarf planet"],
        correct: "An ice giant planet"
    },
    {
        question: "How many moons does Uranus have?",
        options: ["18", "14", "10", "27"],
        correct: "27"
    },
    {
        question: "The axial tilt of Uranus is considered .............",
        options: ["Acute", "Obtuse", "Right", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Right"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the reason for the blue and green color of Uranus?",
        options: ["Presence of water vapor", "Methane gas", "Ammonia ice", "Reflection of sunlight on its rings"],
        correct: "Methane gas"
    },
    {
        question: "Uranus is the ............ planet in distance from the Sun.",
        options: ["Sixth", "Seventh", "Eighth", "Ninth"],
        correct: "Seventh"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the reason for Neptune's blue color?",
        options: ["Methane gas", "Hydrogen", "Helium", "Ammonia"],
        correct: "Methane gas"
    },
    {
        question: "What distinguishes Neptune?",
        options: ["The fastest winds in the solar system", "The least dense planet", "The largest planet", "The planet supporting life"],
        correct: "The fastest winds in the solar system"
    },
    {
        question: "The farthest planet from the Sun is?",
        options: ["Neptune", "Uranus", "Saturn", "Mercury"],
        correct: "Neptune"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of Neptune's moons is?",
        options: ["14", "140", "95", "2"],
        correct: "14"
    },
    {
        question: "The most abundant element on Jupiter's surface is ..........",
        options: ["Hydrogen", "Silicon", "Carbon", "Oxygen"],
        correct: "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
        question: "To which galaxy does our solar system belong?",
        options: ["Milky Way Galaxy", "Andromeda Galaxy", "M87 Galaxy", "Ursa Major Galaxy"],
        correct: "Milky Way Galaxy"
    },
    {
        question: "To what type does the Milky Way galaxy belong?",
        options: ["Spiral", "Elliptical", "Irregular", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Spiral"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following parts is the most massive in the Milky Way galaxy?",
        options: ["The Core", "The Spiral Arms", "Laniakea Supercluster", "The Nebula"],
        correct: "The Core"
    },
    {
        question: "To which arm does our solar system belong?",
        options: ["Centaurus Arm", "Perseus Arm", "Sagittarius Arm", "Orion Arm"],
        correct: "Orion Arm"
    },
    {
        question: "Where are stars formed?",
        options: ["Black Holes", "Neutron Stars", "Nebulae", "Planets"],
        correct: "Nebulae"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following can escape from black holes?",
        options: ["Stars", "Light", "Sound", "Nothing can escape from them"],
        correct: "Nothing can escape from them"
    },
    {
        question: "Who first predicted the existence of black holes?",
        options: ["Schwarzschild", "Einstein", "John Michell", "Newton"],
        correct: "John Michell"
    },
    {
        question: "In which galaxy was a black hole photographed for the first time?",
        options: ["Milky Way Galaxy", "Andromeda Galaxy", "M87 Galaxy", "Ursa Major Galaxy"],
        correct: "M87 Galaxy"
    },
    {
        question: "What produces black holes?",
        options: ["Nebulae", "The death of stars", "Pulsars of neutron stars", "All of the above"],
        correct: "The death of stars"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the types of black holes?",
        options: ["Stellar black holes", "Supermassive black holes", "Intermediate-mass black holes", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    }
];
